Guide to the John D. Krumboltz Papers SC0219
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Papers, Accessio ARCH-2016-137
  - Speeches, Writing, Consulting
    - Expanding Career learning via assessment (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Back to the Future (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Progress of counseling, 2002 Jan 21 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Career development like Tennis, 1995 Jul 6 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Academic Job Search (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Happenstance + Positive Psychology, 2003 Aug 10 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Planning careers in unpredictable world (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Wizard of Oz video (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Learning theory of career coun: SPH (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Counseling as Learning, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Integrating social Learning theory APA presentation, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - C. P. in Educ" transparencies, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Zeteophobia (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Speech "Necessity of College Education" (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Transparency masters: identifying CDM private rules (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Counseling Psychology Definition, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Illustrations "Social learning theory, careers" (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Tyler Award Transparency Masters (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Tyler Award Speech Masters, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - CBI Overhead Masters (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Prediction of Leadership from Extracurricular Participation, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Christal, R.E., and Krumboltz, J.D., Prediction of First Semester Criteria at the Air Force Academy, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Christal, R.E., and Krumboltz, J.D., Use of the Air Force Officer Qualifying Test in the AFROTC Selection Program, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Measuring Achievement Motivation: A Review.", 1957 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Christal, R.E., "Relative Pilot Aptitude and Success in Primary Pilot Straining", 1957 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Physical Proficiency as a Predictor of Leadership, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "The Relation of Extracurricular Participation to Leadership Criteria.", 1957 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Christal R.E., Predictive Validities for First-Year Criteria at the Air Force Academy, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Farquhar, W.W., "Reliability and Validity of the n-Achievement Test.", 1957 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Farquhar, W.W., "The Effect of Three Teaching Methods on Achievement and Motivational Outcomes in a How-to-Study Course.", 1957 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Krumboltz, Helen B., and Krumboltz, J.D., "Birth Rank and Family Size: Relationship to Certain Qualifications of Prospective Teachers.", 1958 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Cox, J.A., and Krumboltz, J.D. "Racial Bias in Peer Ratings of Basic Airmen.", 1958 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Farquhar, W.W., and Krumboltz, J.D., "A Check List for Evaluating Experimental Research in Psychology and Education", 1959 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Christal, R.E. and Ward, Joe H., "Predicting Leadership Ratings from High School Activities", 1959 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "A Note on the Accuracy of Self-Reported Grade Point Averages", 1960 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Christal R.E., "Short-term Practice Effects in Tests of Spatial Aptitude.", 1960 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Krumboltz, J.D. "The Graduate Program in Educational Psychology" in Newsletter, Div. 15 APA, page 8 and 9, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Meaningful Learning and Retention: Practice and Reinforcement Variables", 1961 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - TenBrink, G., and Krumboltz, J.D., "Study Questions as an Aid to Learning.", 1961 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Review of James G. Holland and B.F. Skinner, The Analysis of Behavior, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Bonawitz, B., "The Effect of Receiving the Confirming Response in Context in Programmed Material", 1962 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Krumboltz, J.D. and Weisman, R.G. "The Effect of Overt vs. Convert Responding to Programmed Instruction", 1962 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Weisman, R.G., "The Effect of Overt vs. Covert Responding to Programmed Instruction on Immediate and Delayed Retention, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Counseling for Behavior Change", 1963 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Needed Research in Programmed Instruction", 1963 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Review of Robert Glaser (Ed.), Training Research and Education., 1963 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Subcommittee on Instructional Media and Teacher Education, Survey of Programmed Instruction in Teacher Education, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - 1961-1964 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Factors Effecting Difficulty Level and Criterion Performance, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Factors Affecting Difficulty Level and Criterion Performance", 1964 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Parable of the Good Counselor.", 1964 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Krumboltz, J.D., "Parable of the Good Counselor."The Nature and Importance of the Required Response in Programmed Instruction, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Ryan, T.A. Krumboltz, J.D. "Effect of Planned Reinforcement Counseling on Client Decision-Making Behavior", 1964 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Krumboltz, J.D. Thoresen, C.E. "The Effect of Behavioral Counseling in Group and Individual Settings on Information-Seeking Behavior", 1964 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Hershey, Krumboltz, Shepard, "Effectiveness of Classroom Observation and Simulated Teaching in an Introductory Educational Psychology Course., 1965 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "The Agenda for Counseling", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Behavioral Counseling: Rationale and Research", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Evaluating of Programmed Instruction", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Review of Harold D. Carter, California Study Methods Survey, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Review of Einar R. Ryden, Pictographic Self Rating Scale, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Krumbotlz, J.D., Review of Henry Weitz, Behavior Change through Guidance, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Schroeder, W.W., "Promoting Career Planning through Reinforcement.", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Krumbotlz, J.D., Kiesler, C.A. "The Partial Reinforcement Paradigm and Programmed Instruction", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Varenhorst, Barbara, "Molders of Pupil Attitudes", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., and Yabroff, W.W., "The Comparative Effects of Inductive and Deductive Sequences in Programmed Instruction", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Thoresen, C.E., Krumboltz, J.D. "The Sex Factor in Model Reinforcement Counseling", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Review of Behavior Change through Guidance, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - The outcomes of counseling and psychotherapy: Theory and Research (review), 1966 (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Krumboltz, J.D. Goodwin, D. L. Abstract of final report: Increasing Task oriented behavior: An Experimental Evaluation of Training Teachers in Reinforcement Techniques" Grant, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Krumboltz, Brobst, Gerken, Schmidt, Warnath. "Recommended Roles for Couseling Psychologists in the Development of Counselor Support Personnel" Report of Ed. Training Com., Div. 17 APA, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Behavioral Goals for Counseling" Journal of Counseling Psychology, 13, #2, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., (Ed) "Chapter 1, Promoting Adaptive Behavior: New Answers to Familiar Questions" pub. In JDK Revolution in Counseling: Implication of Behavioral Science. H. Mifflin., 1966 (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Hosford, R.E. "Behavioral Counseling in the Elementary School" in Elementary School Guidance, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Thoresen, Hosford A Study to Determine How Counseling Procedures Can Be Used to Help Students Make Decisions and Plans more Effectively, Final Report, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Review of Volsky, Magoon, Norman, and Hoyt, the Outcomes of Counseling and Psychotherapy: Theory and Research, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 55)
    - Nixon, Stewart B. (Director) and Krumboltz, John D. (Sponsor) Ways by Which Overly Active Students Can be Taught to Concentrate on Study Activity Res., 1966 (Box 25, Folder 56)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., Stating the Goals of Counseling, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 57)
    - Bahavioral Goals for Counseling. Journal of Counseling Psychology, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Emery, J.R. Krumboltz, J.D. "Standard versus Individualized Hierarchies in Desensitization to Reduce Test Anxiety", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Krumboltz, J.D. "Elementary School Behavioral Counseling", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Future Directions for Counseling Research, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Changing the Behavior of Behavior Changers", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Future Directions for Counseling Research", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "Job Simulation as a Means of Encouraging Career Interests", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Krumboltz, J.D., "A Social Learning Approach to Counseling", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Thoresen, C.E. Krumboltz, J.D. "Relationship of Counselor Reinforcement of Selected Responses to External Bahavior", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Non-verbal Factors in the Effectiveness of Models in Counseling (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - An Accountability Model for Counselors (Personal Guidance Journal), 1974 Jun (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Scilligo, P. La consulenza comportamentale, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Review of Snelbecker: "Learning Theory, Instructional Theory Psychoeducational Design" (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Applications of Social Learning Theory of Career Selection Focus on Guidance Vol. 8 No. 3, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Krumboltz, John D. This Chevrolet Can't Float or Fly. In the Counseling Psychologist, Vol. 6 No. 3, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Krumboltz, John D. with Anita M. Mitchell G. Brian Jones A Social Learning Theory of Career Selection, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Review of Behavioral Instruction: An Evaluative Review, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Stimulating Vocational Exploration through Film-mediated Problems Jones and Krumboltz, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Krumboltz, John D., Peltier, Bruce. What Identifies a Counseling Psychologist: Method or Results? In the Counseling Psychologist, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Changing the Behavior of Behavior Changers (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - John Krumboltz: On Behavioral Counseling A Wisconsin Counselor Interview (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Evudence of A Better way to teach Johnson/Ruskin - Contemporary Psych Reviewed by John D. Krumboltz, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - The Future of Counseling, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Annual Reviewof Psychology "Counseling Psych" Krumboltz Becker-Haven, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Krumboltz Duckham-Shoor: "Reward Direction, Not Perfection", 1979 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - "Soc. Learning + CDM" book, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Final report Abstract: "Effect of Alternative CDM Strategies on the Quality of Resulting Decisions, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Relevant Rigorous Research Krumboltz and Mitchell, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Mitchell, A.M., Jones, G.B., Krumboltz, J.D., Social Learning and career decision making, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - "Alternative Methods for Measuring Outcomes of Career Guidance" (AERA paper), 1979 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - K E Hamel CDM training, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Counseling psychology of the future John D. Krumboltz and Michael Menafee, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - A Second Look at the Revolution in Counseling John D. Krumboltz, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Behavioral Approaches to Career Counseling Krumboltz, J.D. Rude S., 1981 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Mitchell, A.M., Jones, G.B., Krumboltz, J.D., Career Development: How we get From here to there, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Krumboltz, "The Unintended Social Consequences of Testing", 1982 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Tests and guidance: What students need (Educational Testing Service Invitational Conference), 1981 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Mentoring as Unintended Teaching (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Krumboltz/Rude/Mitchell/Hamel Kinnier Behaviors Associated with "Good" and "Poor" Outcomes in a simulated career decision, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - "The Effect of Training in Rational Decision Making on the Quality of Simulated Career Decisions" Krumboltz Scherba, Hamel, Mitchell (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - "Decision-making behaviors associated with "Good" and "poor" outcomes in a simulated career decision" Krumboltz, Rude, Hamel, and Mitchell (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Private Rules in career decision making, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Krumboltz Review of Kendall (Ed) Advances in Cognitive Behavioral Research and Therapy, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Krumboltz "A Cognitive-Behavioral Approach to Making Life's Decisions", 1985 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Vocational Interest Inventory, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Krumboltz, J.D. Presuppositions Underlying Computer Use in Career Counseling", 1985 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Teaching a rational approach to career … Krumboltz, Kinnier, Rude, Sherba Hamel, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Research is a Very Good Thing, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Krumboltz: Review of Stone, Counseling Psychology for Contemporary Psychology, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - "The Goals of Education" Krumboltz, Ford, Nichols, Wentzel, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Mitchell and Krumboltz Effects of cognitive restructuring and decision-making training on career indecision, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Krumboltz Review of Russell Behavioral Counseling in Medicine in Contemporary Psychology, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Krumboltz "Learning to Love Learning", 1988 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Cognition and Counseling: A Critical Appraisal APA, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Generating Support for C.P., 1989 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Hallum, A. Krumboltz, JD. "Impact on Parents…", 1989 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Krumboltz and Nichols. Integrating the Social Learning Theory of Career Decision Making, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Reaction: computer career guidance, 1990 Feb (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Krumboltz, J. D. Representing the process of changing jobs, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Krumboltz Review of Coun Psych: Stategies + services Woody, Hansen, Rossberg, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Sampson + Krumboltz "Computer-Assisted Instruction:…", 1991 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Review of Bluhm Computers…, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Wisdom of Indecision, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - "Dangers of Occupationalism", 1992 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - "Brilliant Insights…", 1991 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Krumboltz + Jackson "Career Assessment as a Learning Tool", 1993 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Integrating Career and Personal Counseling, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Hallum Krumboltz "Parents…", 1993 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Embedding Work Values", 1994 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Career Beliefs Inventory, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Yeh "Non-Competitive Grading Policy", 1995 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Competitive Grading Harm, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - "Prevention in Coun. Psych." c Adams, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - "Learning Theory of Career Coun.", 1996 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Vosvick "Career Assess + CBI", 1996 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Krumboltz + Yeh "Competitive Grading…", 1996 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Hu, Krumboltz, Hansen "Car Coun in China", 1997 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Foster, Krumboltz, Ford "Shy Males", 1997 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Conway + JDK "Sensitivity to Marital", 1997 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - JDK + Winzelberg "Technology…", 1997 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Serentipity… JCP, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - "Coun. Actions for new career", 1998 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Three troublesome beliefs, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - "Planned Happenstance…", 1999 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - "school to work…" Worthington, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Pont-Brown, JDK "School violence", 1999 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - JDK + Jackson, Ranier, Yeh "Teaching C.C.", 1999 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - VJE: Try it JDK, Vidalakis, Tyson, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - K + Vidalakis: "Expanding", 2000 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Chang, Yeh, JDK online Support, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Encouraging Research, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - Humor in Counseling, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - School counselors use HLT, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - unlabeled (Box 27, Folder 53)
    - Training peer sexual health, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 54)
    - Happenstance Learning theory, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - Capitalizing on Happenstance, 2011 (Box 27, Folder 56)
    - Veterans creating a New Life, 2014 (Box 27, Folder 57)
    - Beta test: Ad exec. occSim, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ad disk beta test, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Info resources for career simulation (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ad script, 1995 Jul 12 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Choice of occupations, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - OccSim Contracting, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - VJE: information (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - VJE: junior achievement, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - VJE: CGE8Y, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - VJE- Tech, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Brooks/Cole contracts, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Dragon naturally speaking (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Technology- equipped classrooms (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Computer counseling, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Web pages, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Grading lawsuit (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - ERIC (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Research
    - Intuition and rationality in CDM, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Troubled youth research, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Research ideas (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Research possibilities on act career planning data, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Research funds (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Center for research and development on education and employment, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Psychological intimacy project, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - CBI research proposal: intervention techniques (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Computerized word analysis in therapy (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Master copy - questionnaires personal responsibility project (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Finished coding critical incidents (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Chan Research (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Chan: to be coded, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Chan transcripts, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Character education research, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - PH Research data, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - 6 transcripts of first interviews (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Unfinished incidents: Chan (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - The goals of education (final copy) (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Goals of educ. MS (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Handouts: results of personal resp. png, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Final reports: personal resp. proj, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Happenstance mistakes (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Interest learning study (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Learning interests Worthington, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - NAM proposal: VdE, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - NIH proposal, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - NIMH training grant, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Motivating talented at-risk, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - UFO witness interview, 1988 Jun 18 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Sturrock: UFO physical evidence (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Scriven Evaluation thesaurus (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Humor in counseling (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Simon. Social selection and successful altruism (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Effects of Counseling, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Dodge, et al. Mechanisms in the cycle of violence (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Shepard, Roger N. - "Toward a Universal Law of Generalization…" (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Naylor: Factor Analysis- adult sample, 1995 Jun 6 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Naylor: CBI with Strong, 1985-1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - NSF proposal, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Naylor: Four-factor research (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Frank Naylor Study with CBI (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Research funds, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Future role of Coan psych, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Virtual job experience, 1996-1999 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - VJE effects on college students (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Yeh: Asian male identity dev., 2000 Nov 1 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Victim-offender mediation (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Occupational simulation research (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Stress, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Career Beliefs Inventory
    - Ryan-Jones CBI study, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correlations CBI, strong, SDS: P54, 1990 Jun (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Factor Analysis of Scales, 1989 Aug (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - italian factor analysis, 2008 Jan 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Computer format: final CBI (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Career Beliefs Inventory (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - CBI Manual (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Consistency score: CBI Adm Index (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - scale revision (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - rename scales (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - reliability (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - validity (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - CBI manual revision, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - standards for Educ. + Psych testing, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Interpretation of CBI (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - age norms, 1991 Feb (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Changing cognitive distortions (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - CBI interview with Debbie Then (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Market research: CBI + VJE, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - test review of CBI, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Review of CBI (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - CBI Narrative Report (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Ethnic differences, 1990 Nov 9 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - case studies (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - relation to personality (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - relation to interest (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - feedback on CBI guide (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - reliability summaries on CBI (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - CBI data conversion and variables (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - CBI subscales and items, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - adjusted item weight study (Steve Herman) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Misconceptions Research: a problem-oriented perspective (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - University of Missouri: CBI study, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - CBI transparencies: Indiana 8th graders (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - College of St. Rose CBI study, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Lehigh Univ. CBI study-Spokane, 1995 Apr 5 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Research studies on CBI elsewhere, 1999 Jan 29 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - SAS programs for CBI, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - University of Oklahoma: CBI intervention, 1996 Aug 28 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Albany, NY, VA study on CBI (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Carnell: "CBI and Anxiety", 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Holland et al "Validating CBI", 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - VA Hosp. CBI study, 1990 Nov 15 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ford Study: Strong, CBI, AGS, 1991 Jan (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - sex differences on CBI, 1991 Nov 13 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - CBI Research APA, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Maine questionnaire (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Maine counselor data (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Maine follow-up study (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Niles + Sowa: "CBI Correlations" (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Anovas Gender + age (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - University of Oklahoma: study (Fugua), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - CCEC in San Mateo: CBI study, 1990 Aug 30 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - CBI + MBTI (Box 6, Folder 23)